Speaker 1: Here, let me help you get these slippers off.
Speaker 1: You did a great job on that walk.
Speaker 0: You sure did, Ms.
Speaker 0: Adams.
Speaker 0: How are you feeling?
Speaker 2: Well, I'm kind of glad it's over.
Speaker 2: It will get easier, won't it?
Speaker 1: Oh, it will, hon.
Speaker 1: It will.
Speaker 0: That's what we're working towards.
Speaker 0: So if you both look at the board here, it's spelled out.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: Adams, I'm really glad that you're able to be here when we're walking with your wife because I think it's going to give you a better sense of what to expect once you're home and how her recovery is progressing.
Speaker 1: It certainly will.
Speaker 0: Now, we gave her the pain medication an hour before she walked so that she would feel comfortable.
Speaker 0: Then, as you saw, when we got her out of bed, we had her sit on the edge of the bed to make sure she wasn't dizzy from the medications.
Speaker 0: Then we had her stand for a minute to make sure she was okay before she started walking.
Speaker 0: That's going to be important to continue once you're at home.
Speaker 0: And we also talked about how it's important for Ms.
Speaker 0: Adams to get all of her medications on time at home.
Speaker 0: She's on a blood thinner to prevent blood clots, and walking also keeps her blood circulating and will prevent clotting as well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really like that little calendar you showed me that has all the times charted out.
Speaker 1: But, you know, I'm not sure either.
Speaker 1: one of us is clear on the dose of each medicine.
Speaker 2: He's right about that.
Speaker 0: I'm really glad you told me this.
Speaker 0: This is exactly the kind of information I need to know.
Speaker 0: I'll go over the doses now and we'll review them again when Ms.
Speaker 0: Adams is discharged.
Speaker 0: Plus I have some printed materials to give you when you go home as well.
Speaker 1: Thanks.
Speaker 1: That'll be really helpful.